# PAUL OPMANN

# FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

#### CONTACT

+372 56689 018

paul.opmann@gmail.com

paulopmann.com Estonia,

Talling

#### EXPERTISE

- Node.js, Next.js, Nest.js (TypeScript)
- SQL / NoSQL (MongoDB, Redis)
- · AWS, Firebase, Google Cloud
- Elasticsearch, RabbitMQ
- REST / GraphQL API
- Docker
- React, React Native (TypeScript) redux,
- iotai, zuztand
- PostCSS / SCSS
- Tailwind / styled-components webpack
- .
- php, Go, Java, python

#### EDUCATION

#### **BoS - Computer Science 2018-present**

Tallinn University of Technology

Estonia, Tallinn

#### **Exchange Study**

2022-present



South Korea, Seoul

# LANGUAGES

English Advanced

Russian Native

Estonian Upper Intermediate

Korean Elementary

#### ABOUT ME

Passionate problem solver with over 4 years of hands-on experience in full stack web application development, having extensive experience with TypeScript always ready to jump at any opportunity to challenge and further improve his skillset.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Full Stack Developer**

Lawato (co-founder)

2022/07-present

- · Managed cloud infrastructure and optimized services to minimize costs. Designed,
- developed, and took part in the implementation of the architecture for the MVP of the SaaS.

#### **Full Stack Developer**

Lumav Commerce [remote]

11/2021-11/2022

- Optimized the performance of existing PWA applications.
- Built custom functionality modules for Magento 2 powered e-commerce applications.
- Implemented new and adjusted existing features in accordance with client requirements, software specification and design.

#### **Full Stack Developer**

Havas Estonia

Estonia, Tallinn

02/2021-06/2021

- Built and managed back-end microservices.
- Translated provided designs into UI elements.
- Engaged in the process of cross-platform mobile application development.

#### **Full Stack Developer**

Freelance [remote]

2020-present

- Consulted clients on the technical requirements and potential costs.
- Built custom page parsers for data export.
- Built custom automation scripts and browser extensions.
- Engaged in the development of software MVP as both FE and BE developer..

## **Back End Developer**

Pipedrive

Estonia, Tallinn

08/2019-05/2020

- · Built and managed back-end microservices.
- Leveraged Agile methodologies to move the development lifecycle rapidly through initial prototyping to enterprise-quality testing and final implementation. Took part in
- the on-call rotation.
- Created and managed existing APIs.